aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
Vicious prisoners escaped from the Space Prison of Sargasso, and have begun their planetary galley.
우주감옥 사르갓소의 흉악한 우주인들이 혹성 사냥을 개시했다
In order to protect the peace of Earth,
지구의 평화를 지키기 위해
Brave Seijin of the Space Police granted these heroes powers.
우주 경찰 기구의 브레이브 성인이 힘을 내려준 용자(勇者)들
Their name is Dagwon.
그 이름은 다그온
Now, a new comrade has joined them.
그들에게 지금 새로운 동료가 가담했다
Charge! Dag Drill
돌격! 다그 드릴
Space Merchant Nouvelle Seijin
Appears
우주 상인 누벨 성인
등장
Everyone come!
모두 모여랏!
All Dagwons, gather to Dag Base right now!
당장 다그 베이스로 다그온 전원 집합이닷!
Look at my Drill Liner!
잘 봐라, 나의 드릴 라이너를
What do ya think? Shiny!
어때, 번쩍번쩍하지?
I've been cleaning this all night.
뭐, 밤을 꼬박 새서 닦았으니까 말야
Don't call us for things like that!
그런 일로 일일이 불러내지 말라구!
Please think before calling us.
좀 봐주세요
I was almost kissing with Erika, and you woke me up for that?!
조금만 더 였으면 에리카 쨩과 키스할 수 있었는데 그걸 깨우냐?!
You first disturbed the disciplines of the school, and now you disturbed our sleep.
학교의 풍기를 흐리더니만, 이젠 우리 잠까지 흐리다니...
Unforgivable!
용서 못한다!
Are you an alien from Sargasso?
너, 사르갓소의 우주인이냐?!
Brave Seijin.
브레이브 성인
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온!
Drill Geki!
드릴 게키!
Dagwon?!
다그온?!
Hurry and run away!
어서 도망치시오!
Drill Crush!
드릴 크러시!
I am that Drill Geki!
바로 내가 드릴 게키!
Don't be too excited for things like that!
쓸데없이 흥분해서 말야
You bother us a lot!
이쪽은 큰 폐를 입고 있다구
If you have time for that, just go for a patrol!
나 참, 그럴 틈이 있으면 말야 정찰이나 하란 말이다
What did you say?!
뭐, 뭣이?!
Wanna fight?
한판 해볼래?
Stop it, you two.
그만둬, 둘 다
You are right! You're my true friend, En!
네 말이 백번 옳다! 과연 나의 친구, 엔!
Great! If you say so, we'll go on a patrol of friendship!
좋아! 그렇게 정했으면, 둘이서 우정의 정찰이다!
Let's launch!
자, 발진!
Hey, wait! Hey! Stop! Geki,, wait!
이봐! 자, 자, 잠깐 기다려! 야, 게키! 기다려!
Huh? They actually went on one.
어레레? 진짜로 둘이서 가 버렸어
What simple fellows.
정말 단순한 녀석들이라니깐
Birds of a feather flock together, as always.
역시 유유상종이군 (역주 : 類は友を呼ぶ -속담입니다)
Everything is the first class of the century!
어느 것도 틀림없는 세기 일류
Now, who'd like to make a bid?
그럼, 어느 분께서 구입하시렵니까?
One Statue of Liberty.
자유의 여신상 하나
Yes! Lord Minaki Seijin, you are awarded one Statue of Liberty!
예이~ 미나키 성인 님, 자유의 여신상 낙찰
Isn't it peaceful?
하지만, 평화로운걸?
I just wanted to show everyone my activity!
내 활약을 모두에게 보여주고 싶은데 말야
Right, En?
안그래, 엔?
Shut up! What is this patrol of friendship?
시끄러! 무슨 얼어죽을 우정의 정찰이냐?
You just took me along without asking me!
남을 멋대로 끌고 와서 말야
I have an itch for something interesting!
왠지 심심해서 근질근질 하구만
Aren't you, En?
안그래, 엔?
Hey, you! Are you listening to me?
너 말야! 내 말 듣고 있냐?!
Watch where you're going!
위험하잖아! 조심하라구!
They're waving hands to us!
엇? 손 흔들고 있구만
Hey!
안녕하슈~
You asshole!
바보자식!
You poor driver! Are you trying to kill me?
이 허접 자식아! 날 죽일 셈이냐?!
What was that for?!
무, 무슨 짓이냐?!
Riding this thing, multiple lives won't be enough!
이딴거에 타고 있으면 목숨이 몇개라도 부족하다구!
Are you finding faults with Drill Liner and me?
나와 드릴 라이너를 트집잡는 거냐?!
Even for a friend, unforgivable!
친구라고 해도 용서 못한다!
Then drive it carefully!
그럼 제대로 조종하란 말이다!
Shut up, nitpicker!
입 다물라, 트집쟁이 녀석!
-Like you did something great!
-What?!
-뭘 잘했다고 이러냐?!
-뭣이?!
You nitwit ragpicker!
이 덜떨어진 양아치 녀석!
What did you say?!
뭐, 뭐라고?!
Don't scare me like that!
놀래키치 말라구
What the-?
뭐지?!
What is that?!
저, 저건?!
We came too far!
이렇게 먼 곳까지 와 버린 건가
You damn alien from Sargasso! It is your bad luck to encounter me, the great Geki!
사르갓소의 우주인 녀석 이 게키님과 만난걸 불행으로 여겨라
Do not interfere!
방해하지 마라!
-What are you doing, Geki?!
-I know already!
-뭘 하는 거냐, 게키?!
-나도 알고 있어!
This castle is our objective.
목적의 성이다
What the hell?!
뭐, 뭐야?!
How's that, En?
어떠냐, 엔?!
Hmph, this is...
흥, 이정도는 말야...
Did I fail?
실패한 건가?!
Hey, hey! What's going...
어이, 이봐! 뭐가 어떻게 된 거...
Crystal?!
수, 수정?!
En?
에, 엔이야?
G-Gaku? What are you doing here?
가, 가쿠? 너 여기서 뭐해?
Did you leave your home?
설마 가출한 거냐?
Idiot! I'm on a picnic!
바보, 소풍 나온 거야
We had time to move freely and I got lost.
자유 행동이라 애들이랑 떨어졌다가 이런 일을...
No doubt. Aliens did this!
틀림없어, 이건 우주인의 짓이야
What is this crystal prison?
이 수정 감옥은 뭐지?
No need to worry!
걱정할 필요 없수다!
I've already taken down the enemy spaceship.
적 우주인은 이미 우주선 째로 격추시켰소
That guy made this cumbersome prison as his last ditch fight,
그녀석, 최후의 발악으로 이런 성가신 감옥을 만들었지만
but leave it to me, and you're going to escape soon!
내게 맡겨두시면 바로 탈출할 수 있소!
-Who the heck are you?
-Wha?
-누구야, 너는?
-뭐이?
Gaku?
가쿠...군?
"Leave it to me," and you didn't even introduced yourself!
난데없이 "내게 맡겨두쇼" 라니
Who the heck are you?
도대체 뭐하는 놈이냐, 넌?
Me?
나 말인가?
I'll let you know!
후훗, 가르쳐 주지
Ehem! My name is Drill Geki!
어험! 내 이름은 드릴 게키!
Look at me! I am the sixth Dagwon!
어떠냐, 내가 바로 6번째 다그온이다!
Even if you say so, you're just an imitation of Dagwon!
그런 말이나 하고, 짜가 다그온이잖아
What's that?
뭣이?
Whatever you say, I don't know any such Dagwon!
하지만, 그런 다그온 몰라
Signed, self-appointed number one of Dagwon Club!
자칭 다그온 클럽 회원 넘버 1인
It is true, since I get to declare it!
내가 하는 소리니까 틀림없어!
Hey, wait a moment!
기, 기다려봐!
I am just a recently appointed Dagwon...
난 이번에 들어온 신인 다그온인데...
He's in trouble. He's suffering!
곤란해 하고 있구만, 곤란해 하고 있어
Ahh, a recruit is all hard work!
아아~ 신인은 고달픈 신세지
Okay, I get it! I get it!
알았어, 알았다구!
I'll let all of you escape from here and you won't complain ever again!
빈틈없이 모두를 여기에서 탈출시키면 군소리 없겠지?!
This is the potential of Drill Geki!
이게 바로 드릴 게키의 저력이닷!
-This is no good.
글렀구만, 이거...
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Good grief! A simple-minded dimwit isn't really useful.
정말, 단세포인데다가 돌머리여선 못 써먹는다구
When above the ground doesn't work, he could come out with an idea of escaping below!
땅 위가 글렀다면 지하로 탈출한다는 발상 정도는 해야지
What's that? That's my idea.
뭐야, 내 아이디어잖아
But really, with that new Dagwon,
하지만 정말, 그 신인 다그온에게 맡겨 두었다간
I don't know what'll happen.
어떻게 될지 모르겠는걸
He's with spirit, but he has nothing else.
기합은 들어가 있지만, 전혀 도움이 안되는 것 같고 말야
What's the problem? Do you see an escape?
왜그래? 탈출할 수 있을 것 같아?
This crystal is too well-made!
수정 한번 잘 만들었구만
I'm tired. What should we do?
이제 지쳤어 이제부터 어떻게 하지?
You guys!
이자식들!
How dare you mess up with the auction of us Nouvelle Seijin!
잘도 우리 누벨 성인의 경매를 망쳐놨군!
You guys are from that spaceship...
너희들은 아까 그 우주선의?!
How are you still alive?!
살아 있었단 말인가?!
We'll be paid by your lives!
너희들의 목숨으로 보상받아야겠다!
Is that the crystalized city?
크리스탈화 된 마을은 저건가?
Something's not right.
이상합니다!
The temperature inside that crystal is quickly increasing!
저 크리스탈 내부, 온도가 급상승 중입니다!
I see! The crystal is concentrating solar rays like a lens!
그렇군! 수정이 렌즈 역할을 해서 태양 광선을!
Look at that!
저길 봐!
Why?!
어째서냐?!
What a pity! Can't you break this single wall?
이런 벽 하나 못 부수다니, 한심하다!
What's going on? What's wrong?
뭐, 뭐지? 어떻게 된거야?!
Everyone...
여러분...
I can't go on...
더, 더이상은 안되겠어
Get a grip, Gaku!
정신차려, 가쿠!
En!
엔!
Hmph. That isn't enough.
흥! 필요없어
Don't follow me!
오, 오지마!
Die!
뒈져라!
Stop!
기다려라!
Dagwon!
다그온!
Shoulder Burn!
숄더 번!
Are you alright, Gaku?
괜찮아, 가쿠?!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!
Dag Turbo!
다그 터보!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!
Dag Armor!
다그 아머!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!
Dag Wing!
다그 윙!
Break Wheel!
브레이크 호일!
Final Buster!
파이널 버스터!
Crystal Cutter!
크리스탈 커터!
It's not working.
통하지 않는 건가
What the-?!
뭐, 뭐지?!
Is that guy behind this?!
저녀석이 사건의 장본인인가?!
The crystal statue transport ship has arrived.
크리스탈 상의 수송선이 도착했군
What did you say?!
뭐, 뭐라고?!
You guys shall become the perfect crystal statue with the Crystal Laser, and be sold to alien riches by auction!
너희들도 크리스탈 레이저도 훌륭한 크리스탈 상이 돼서 경매로 부자 우주인에게 팔리는게 좋을거다
So hot...
더워...
Gaku?
가쿠?
Gaku!
가쿠!
Damn!
제길!
Gaku is right...
가쿠의 말대로다
I am an untrustworthy Dagwon who cannot save even a single person!
난 누구 하나 구하지 못하는 정말 못미더운 다그온이다!
En?
엔?!
You bastard!
이자식!
What was that for?!
무슨 짓이냐?!
Were you a helpless dimwit who already gives up?
이정도로 단념할 약해빠진 녀석이었냐?!
You lied to us!
거짓말 친 거냐?!
What a pitiful Dagwon!
정말 한심한 다그온이군!
What?!
뭐라고?!
You think you're a real a Dagwon?!
그러고도 진짜 다그온이냐?!
En...
엔...
You are now the only one who can save all of us!
지금 이 위기를 구해낼 수 있는건 너밖에 없단 말이다!
I... I'm sorry!
내가... 내가 잘못했다!
Geki...
게키!
Alright! I'll show the true will of a real Dagwon!
좋아! 진짜 다그온의 의지를 보여주마!
Break Wheel!
브레이크 호일!
Spiral Launcher!
파이널 버스터!
Blizzard Typhon!
블리자드 타이푼!
Shadow Shuriken!
섀도우 수리검!
It's no use! Soon the city will be...
틀렸어! 이대론 마을이!
Show your true guts, Drill Liner!
너의 근성을 보여줘라, 드릴 라이너!
Geki!
게키!
I'm not losing with this!
이정도로 질 성 싶으냐?!
I'm a...
나는...!
Do your best, Drill Geki!
히, 힘내... 드릴 게키!
I'm a...
나는...!
Dagwon!
다그온이다!
That's-!
저건?!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!
Dag Drill!
다그 드릴!
Drill Attack Mode!
드릴 어택 모드!
Wh-what?!
아, 아니?!
Impossible!
말도 안돼!
Dag Drill!
다그 드릴!
Da- Dag Drill?
다, 다그 드릴?!
Is that the kingpin?
저녀석이 두목인가?!
Let's go!
간닷!
Drill Pulse!
드릴 펄스!
How impudent!
건방진 녀석!
Drill Crush!
드릴 크러시!
He made a hole to the armor
이, 이 장갑을 뚫다니?!
Dag Drill, huh? A new reliable comrade.
다그 드릴인가... 믿음직한 동료가 늘었군
Hey!
여어!
That was a wonderful power, Dag Drill! According to my calculations...
엄청난 힘입니다, 다그 드릴! 제 계산에 의하면...
Hmph! You took the stage at the last moment!
쳇! 마지막에 좋은 부분을 뺏긴 느낌이구만
What can we do now? Let's just give him a lift!
뭐, 할 수 없지 오늘만은 좀 추겨세워 줄까?
That's right! That's right!
그렇지, 그렇지
I must do this.
할 수 없지
As the number one of Dagwon Club, I'll approve you, as a real Dagwon!
다그온 클럽 회원 넘버 1도 인정해 줄게 진짜 다그온이라고 말야
Gaku!
가쿠 군!
I see!
그래!
Hey, are you crying?
어레, 울고 있는 거야?
That's not it! This is...
아, 아니야! 이건...
This is the sweat of spirit!
이건 마음의 땀이라구!
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
tooku kirameita
kaze no naka no PRISM
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
Something's not right! Aliens are attacking us!
이상합니다! 우주인들이 습격해오고 있습니다!
What's so weird about that? That happens all the time!
어디가 이상하다는 거냐? 항상 있는 일이잖아?
But, Phoenix Seijin, Killad Seijin, and Gallon Seijin...
하지만, 피닉스 성인과 키라드 성인과 가론 성인과...
What did you say? Didn't we take down all of them?
뭐라고?! 전에 쓰러뜨린 녀석들 뿐이잖아!
Something frightening must be controlling them! It must be a powerful foe!
분명, 이 뒤에는 무서운 무언가가 저들을 조종하고 있는게 틀림없습니다! 강적이라구요!
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! Man! Tears of the Friendship Fusion!
다음회 용자지령 다그온
사나이! 눈물의 우정합체
In other words, Dag Drill is combining!
즉, 다그 드릴이 합체가 합체하는 겁니다!
With who?
대체 누구랑?!
Man!
Tears of the Friendship Fusion
사나이! 눈물의 우정합체